Cleaned, corrected, some OCR errors
fixed and some timings optimized by Tronar
Echo Three to Echo Seven.
Han, old buddy,
do you read me?
Loud and clear, kid.
What's up?
Well, I finished my circle.
I don't pick up any life readings.
There isn't enough life on this ice cube
to fill a space cruiser.
The sensors are placed.
I'm going back.
Right. I'll see you shortly.
There's a meteorite
that hit the ground near here.
I want to check it out.
It won't take long.
Steady.
Steady, girl. What's the matter?
You smell something?
Chewie. Chewie?
All right.
Don't lose your temper.
I'll come right back
and give you a hand.
Solo.
No sign of life out there, General.
The sensors are in place.
- You'll know if anything comes around.
- Commander Skywalker reported in yet?
No. He's checking out
a meteorite that hit near him.
With all the meteor activity, it's gonna
be difficult to spot approaching ships.
General, I gotta leave.
I can't stay any more.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- There's a price on my head.
If I don't pay off Jabba the Hutt,
I'm a dead man.
A death mark's not
an easy thing to live with.
You're a good fighter, Solo.
I hate to lose you.
Thank you, General.
Well, Your Highness,
guess this is it.
That's right.
Don't get all mushy on me.
So long, Princess.
Han.
- Yes, Your Highnessness.
- I thought you had decided to stay.
The bounty hunter we ran into
in Ord Mantell changed my mind.
Han, we need you.
- We need?
- Yes.
- What about you need?
- I need?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- You probably don't.
- What precisely am I supposed to know?
Come on. You want me to stay because
of the way you feel about me.
Yes. You're a great help to us.
You're a natural leader.
No. That's not it.
Come on.
- Come on.
- You're imagining things.
Am I?
Then why are you following me?
Afraid I'd leave
without giving you a goodbye kiss?
- I'd just as soon kiss a Wookiee.
- I can arrange that.
You could use a good kiss!
Don't blame me. I didn't ask you
to turn on the thermal heater.
I merely commented that it was freezing
in the princess's chamber.
It's supposed to be freezing.
How we're going to dry
her clothes I really don't know.
Oh, switch off!
Why did you take this apart now?
I'm trying to get us out of here.
- Excuse me.
- Put them back together right now.
- Might I have a word?
- What do you want?
Princess Leia's been trying
to get you on the communicator.
I turned it off.
I don't want to talk to her.
Princess Leia is wondering about
Master Luke. He hasn't come back.
- She doesn't know where he is.
- I don't know where he is.
- Nobody knows where he is.
- What do you mean, nobody knows?
Deck Officer.
- Deck Officer.
- Excuse me, sir. Might I...
Do you know where
Commander Skywalker is?
I haven't seen him. It's possible
he came in the south entrance.
It's possible?
Why don't you go find out?
- It's getting dark out there.
- Yes, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
Might I enquire what's going on?
- Why not?
- Impossible man.
Come along, R2.
Let's find Princess Leia.
Between ourselves, I think
Master Luke is in considerable danger.
Commander Skywalker
hasn't come in the south entrance.
- Maybe he forgot to check in.
- Not likely. Are the speeders ready?
Not yet. We're having trouble
adapting them to the cold.
- We'll have to go out on tauntauns.
- The temperature's dropping too rapidly.
That's right,
and my friend's out in it.
Your tauntaun will freeze
before you reach the first marker.
Then I'll see you in hell.
You must come along now, R2.
There's really
nothing more we can do.
And my joints are freezing up.
Don't say things like that.
Of course we'll see Master Luke again.
And he'll be quite all right.
You'll see.
Stupid little short circuit.
He'll be quite all right.
Sir, all the patrols are in.
Still no...
Still no contact
from Skywalker or Solo.
Mistress Leia, R2 says he's been
quite unable to pick up any signals...
although he admits that his own range
is far too weak to abandon all hope.
Your Highness,
there's nothing more we can do tonight.
The shield doors must be closed.
- Close the doors.
- Yes, sir.
R2 says the chances
of survival are 725-to-1.
Actually, R2 has been known
to make mistakes...
from time to time.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
Don't worry about Master Luke.
I'm sure he'll be all right.
He's quite clever, you know,
for a human being.
Luke.
Ben?
You will go to
the Dagobah system.
Dagobah system?
There you will
learn from Yoda...
the Jedi master
who instructed me.
Don't do this, Luke.
Give me a sign here.
- Not much time.
- Ben.
Hang on, kid.
Dagobah system. Dagobah.
This may smell bad, kid...
Yoda.
But it'll keep you warm
till I get the shelter up.
Ben. Dagobah.
I thought they smelled bad...
on the outside.
Echo Base, I've got something.
Not much,
but it could be a life form.
Commander Skywalker,
do you copy?
This is Rogue Two.
Captain Solo, do you copy?
Commander Skywalker,
do you copy?
This is Rogue Two.
Good morning.
Nice of you guys to drop by.
Echo Base, this is Rogue Two.
I've found them.
Repeat. I've found them.
Master Luke, sir, it's so good
to see you fully functional again.
- Thanks, 3PO.
- R2 expresses his relief also.
How ya feelin', kid?
You don't look so bad to me.
You look strong enough
to pull the ears off a gundark.
- Thanks to you.
- That's two you owe me, junior.
Well, Your Worship...
looks like you managed to keep me around
for a little while longer.
I had nothing to do with it.
General Rieekan thinks
it's dangerous for any ships to leave...
until we've activated the energy field.
That's a good story.
I think you just can't bear to let a
gorgeous guy like me out of your sight.
I don't know where
you get your delusions, laser brain.
Laugh it up, fuzzball...
but you didn't see us alone
in the south passage.
She expressed
her true feelings for me.
My...
Why, you stuck-up, half-witted...
scruffy-looking nerf herder!
Who's scruffy-lookin'?
I must have hit close to the mark
to get her riled up like that, huh, kid?
I guess you don't know
everything about women yet.
Headquarters personnel,
report to command center.
Take it easy.
Excuse us, please.
Princess, we have a visitor.
We picked up something
outside Zone 12 moving east.
- It's metal.
- It couldn't be one of those creatures.
- Could be one of our speeders.
- No. Wait.
There's something
very weak coming through.
Sir, I am fluent in six million
forms of communication.
This signal is not used by the Alliance.
It could be an imperial code.
It isn't friendly.
Chewie, let's check it out.
Send Rogues 10 and 11
to Station 38.
- I'm afraid there's not much left.
- What was it?
Droid of some kind.
I didn't hit it that hard.
- Must have had a self-destruct.
- An imperial probe droid.
It's a good bet the Empire
knows we're here.
We'd better start the evacuation.
- Admiral.
- Yes, Captain?
I think we've got something, sir.
The report is only a fragment...
from a probe droid in the Hoth system,
but it's the best lead we've had.
We have thousands of probe droids
searching the galaxy.
- I want proof, not leads.
- The visuals indicate life readings.
It could mean anything.
If we followed up every lead...
But, sir, the Hoth system is
supposed to be devoid of humans forms.
- You found something?
- Yes, my lord.
That's it.
The rebels are there.
My lord, there are so many
uncharted settlements.
- It could be smugglers...
- That is the system.
And I'm sure Skywalker is with them.
Set your course
for the Hoth system.
General Veers,
prepare your men.
Admiral.
Groups Seven and 10
will stay behind to fly the speeders.
As soon as each transport is loaded...
evacuation control will give
clearance for immediate launch.
Right, sir.
All right. That's it.
Try it.
Turn it off! Turn it off!
Sir, it will take quite a while
to evacuate the T-47s.
Forget the heavy equipment. There's time
to get small modules on the transports.
- Take care, sir.
- Thanks.
Chewie, take care of yourself, okay?
Okay, okay.
Hi, kid.
There's gotta be a reason for it.
Check it at the other end.
Wait a second.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Be careful.
You too.
General, there's
a fleet of Stardestroyers...
coming out of hyperspace
in Sector Four.
Reroute all power
to the energy shield.
We gotta hold them till
all transports are away.
Prepare for ground assault.
- What is it, General?
- The fleet has moved out of light speed.
ComScan has detected
an energy field...
protecting an area of the sixth planet
of the Hoth system.
The field is strong enough
to deflect any bombardment.
The rebels are alerted
to our presence.
Admiral Ozzel came out of light speed
too close to the system.
He felt surprise was wiser.
He is as clumsy as he is stupid.
General, prepare your troops
for a surface attack.
Yes, my lord.
Lord Vader.
The fleet has moved out of light speed,
and we're preparing to...
You have failed me
for the last time, Admiral.
- Captain Piett.
- Yes, my lord?
Make ready to land our troops
beyond their energy field...
and deploy the fleet so that
nothing gets off the system.
You are in command now,
Admiral Piett.
Thank you, Lord Vader.
All troop carriers will assemble
at the north entrance.
The heavy transport ships
will leave as soon as they're loaded.
Only two fighter escorts per ship.
The energy shield
can only be opened for a short time...
so you'll have to stay very close
to your transports.
Two fighters against a Stardestroyer?
The ion cannon will fire
several shots...
to make sure that any enemy ships
will be out of your flight path.
When you've gotten past
the energy shield...
proceed directly
to the rendezvous point.
Understood?
Good luck.
Everybody to your stations.
Let's go.
Their primary target will be
the power generators.
Prepare to open shield.
Sir, rebel ships are
coming into our sector.
Good. Our first catch of the day.
Stand by, ion control.
Fire.
The first transport is away.
Feeling all right, sir?
Just like new, Dak.
How about you?
Right now I feel I could take on
the whole Empire myself.
I know what you mean.
Echo Station 3-T8.
We've spotted imperial walkers.
Imperial walkers
on the north ridge.
Echo Station 57,
we're on our way.
All right, boys,
keep tight now.
Luke, I have no approach vector.
I'm not set.
Steady, Dak.
Attack pattern Delta.
Go now.
I'm coming in.
Hobbie, you still with me?
That armor's too strong for blasters.
Rogue Group,
use your harpoons and tow cables.
Go for the legs.
It might be our only chance.
Stand by, Dak.
Luke, we've got
a malfunction in fire control.
I'll have to cut in the auxiliary.
Just hang on.
Hang on, Dak.
Get ready to fire that tow cable.
Dak?
Yes, Lord Vader.
I've reached the main power generators.
The shield will be down in moments.
You may start your landing.
Rogue Three.
Copy, Rogue Leader.
Wedge, I've lost my gunner.
You'll have to make this shot.
I'll cover for you.
Set your harpoon.
Follow me on the next pass.
Coming around, Rogue Leader.
Steady, Rogue Two.
Activate harpoon.
Good shot, Janson.
One more pass.
Cable out.
Let her go!
Detach cable.
Cable detached.
Come on!
- That got him!
- I see it, Wedge. Good work.
I don't think we can protect
two transports at a time.
It's risky, but we can't
hold out much longer.
We have no choice.
- Launch patrol.
- Evacuate remaining ground staff.
This one goes there,
that one goes there. Right?
R2, you take good care
of Master Luke now, understand?
And do take good care of yourself.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
All troops will debark
for ground assault.
Prepare to target
the main generator.
- Rogue Two, are you all right?
- Yeah. I'm with you, Rogue Leader.
Set harpoon.
I'll cover for you.
- Coming around.
- Watch that crossfire, boys.
Set for position three.
Steady.
Stay tight and low.
This is it!
Hobbie!
I've been hit!
- You all right?
- Why are you still here?
- Heard the command center had been hit.
- You've got your clearance to leave.
Don't worry. I'll leave.
First I'm gonna get you to your ship.
Your Highness, we must take
this last transport. It's our only hope.
Send all troops in Sector 12 to
the south slope to protect the fighters.
Imperial troops
have entered the base.
Imperial troops have entered...
Come on. That's it.
Give the evacuation code signal.
And get to your transports.
Wait for me.
Begin retreat!
Fall back!
- Distance to power generators?
- 17.28.
Target. Maximum firepower.
Transport, this is Solo.
Take off. I can't get to you.
I'll get her out on the Falcon.
Come on.
Where are you going?
Come back!
Wait! Wait for me! Stop!
- How typical.
- Come on.
Hurry up, goldenrod!
You're gonna be a permanent resident.
Wait! Wait!
- How's this?
- Would it help if I got out and pushed?
- Captain Solo. Captain Solo.
- It might.
Sir, might I suggest that you...
It can wait.
This bucket of bolts
will never get past that blockade.
This baby's got
a few surprises left in her.
Come on! Come on!
Switch over.
Let's hope we don't have a burnout.
See?
Someday you're gonna be wrong.
I just hope I'm there to see it.
Punch it!
R2.
Get her ready for take-off.
Good luck, Luke.
See you at the rendezvous.
Don't worry, R2.
We're going. We're going.
There's nothing wrong, R2.
I'm just setting a new course.
We're not gonna regroup with the others.
We're going to the Dagobah system.
Yes, R2.
That's all right. I'd like to keep it
on manual control for a while.
- I saw 'em! I saw 'em!
- Saw what?
Stardestroyers,
two of'em coming right at us.
- Sir, might I suggest...
- Shut him up or shut him down!
Check the deflector shield.
Great. Well, we can still
outmaneuver them.
Take evasive action!
- Prepare to jump to light speed.
- But, sir!
They're getting closer.
Oh, yeah?
Watch this.
Watch what?
- I think we're in trouble.
- If I may say so...
I noticed earlier the hyperdrive
motivator has been damaged.
- It's impossible to go to light speed.
- We're in trouble.
Horizontal boosters!
Alluvial dampers.
That's not it.
Bring me the hydrospanner.
I don't know how
we're gonna get out of this one.
Chewie!
That wasn't a laser blast.
Something hit us.
Han, get up here.
Come on, Chewie!
Asteroids.
- Chewie, set 271.
- What are you doing?
You're not actually going
into an asteroid field?
They'd be crazy to follow us,
wouldn't they?
You don't have to do this
to impress me.
Sir, the possibility of successfully
navigating an asteroid field...
- is approximately 3,720-to-1.
- Never tell me the odds.
You said you wanted to be around when
I made a mistake. This could be it.
I take it back.
We're gonna get pulverized
if we stay out here much longer.
- Ain't gonna argue with that.
- Pulverized?
I'm going closer
to one of the big ones.
- Closer?
This is suicide!
There's nowhere to go.
There. That looks pretty good.
What looks pretty good?
Yeah. That'll do nicely.
Excuse me, ma'am,
but where are we going?
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Yeah. Me too.
Yep, that's it. Dagobah.
No, I'm not gonna change
my mind about this.
I'm not picking up
any cities or technology.
Massive life form readings though.
There's something alive down there.
Yes. I'm sure
it's perfectly safe for droids.
I know! I know!
All the scopes are dead.
I can't see a thing.
Just hang on.
I'm gonna start the landing cycle.
No, R2, you stay put.
I'll have a look around.
R2?
Where are you?
R2!
You be more careful.
R2, that way.
R2!
Oh, no.
Are you all right?
Come on.
You were lucky
to get out of there.
Anything broken?
If you're saying
coming here was a bad idea...
I'm beginning to agree with ya.
R2, what are we doing here?
It's like...
something out of a dream or...
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just going crazy.
Yes, Admiral?
Our ships have sighted
the Millennium Falcon, lord...
but it has entered an asteroid field,
and we cannot risk...
Asteroids do not
concern me, Admiral.
- I want that ship, not excuses.
- Yes, lord.
I'm gonna shut down everything
but the emergency power systems.
Sir, I'm almost afraid to ask, but does
that include shutting me down too?
No. I need you
to talk to the Falcon...
find out what's wrong
with the hyperdrive.
Sir, it's quite possible
this asteroid is not entirely stable.
Not entirely stable?
I'm glad you're here
to tell us these things.
Chewie, take the professor in the back
and plug him into the hyperdrive.
Sometimes I just don't
understand human behaviour.
After all, I'm only
trying to do my job.
Let go.
- Let go, please.
- Don't get excited.
Captain, being held by you
isn't quite enough to get me excited.
Sorry, sweetheart.
I haven't got time
for anything else.
Ready for some power?
Okay.
Let's see now.
Put that in there.
There you go.
Now all I gotta do
is find this Yoda...
if he even exists.
It's really a strange place
to find a Jedi master.
This place gives me the creeps.
Still...
there's something familiar
about this place.
I don't know.
- I feel like...
- Feel like what?
Like we're being watched.
Away put your weapon.
I mean you no harm.
I am wondering,
why are you here?
- I'm looking for someone.
- Looking?
Found someone you have,
I would say.
Right.
Help you I can. Yes.
I don't think so.
I'm looking for a great warrior.
Great warrior.
Wars not make one great.
Put that down.
Hey! That's my dinner.
How you get so big
eating food of this kind?
Listen, friend, we didn't mean
to land in that puddle.
If we could get our ship out, we would.
But we can't.
Aw, cannot get your ship out.
Get out of there.
Hey, you could have broken this.
Don't do that.
You're making a mess.
Hey, give me that.
Mine, or I will help you not.
I don't want your help.
I want my lamp back.
I'm gonna need it to get out of
this slimy mud-hole.
Mud-hole? Slimy?
My home this is.
R2, let him have it.
- Mine! Mine! Mine!
- R2.
Will you move along, little fella?
We got a lot of work to do.
Stay and help you I will.
Find your friend.
I'm not looking for a friend.
I'm looking for a Jedi master.
Jedi master. Yoda.
- You seek Yoda.
- You know him?
Take you to him I will.
Yes, yes, but now we must eat.
Come.
Good food. Come.
Come, come.
R2...
stay and watch after the camp.
Where is R2 when I need him?
Sir, I don't know where your ship
learned to communicate...
but it has the most peculiar dialect.
I believe it says the power coupling
on the negative axis has been polarized.
I'm afraid you'll have to replace it.
Well, of course
I'll have to replace it.
Here. And, Chewie...
I think we better replace
the negative power coupling.
Hey, Your Worship,
I'm only trying to help.
Would you please
stop calling me that?
Sure, Leia.
- You make it so difficult sometimes.
- I do. I really do.
You could be a little nicer though.
Admit it.
Sometimes you think I'm all right.
Occasionally, maybe...
when you aren't acting
like a scoundrel.
Scoundrel?
I like the sound of that.
- Stop that.
- Stop what?
Stop that.
My hands are dirty.
My hands are dirty too.
What are you afraid of?
- Afraid?
- You're trembling.
I'm not trembling.
You like me because I'm a scoundrel.
There aren't enough
scoundrels in your life.
I happen to like nice men.
- I'm a nice man.
- No, you're not.
Sir, sir!
I've isolated
the reverse power flux coupling.
Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- You're perfectly welcome, sir.
That, Lord Vader, was the last time
they appeared in any of our scopes.
Considering the damage we've sustained,
they must have been destroyed.
No, Captain, they're alive.
I want every ship available to sweep
the asteroid field until they are found.
- Lord Vader.
- Yes, Admiral. What is it?
The emperor commands you
to make contact with him.
Move the ship out of
the asteroid field...
so that we can send
a clear transmission.
Yes, my lord.
What is thy bidding, my master?
There is a great disturbance
in the Force.
I have felt it.
We have a new enemy...
the young rebel who destroyed
the Death Star.
I have no doubt this boy...
is the offspring of Anakin Skywalker.
How is that possible?
Search your feelings, Lord Vader.
You will know it to be true.
He could destroy us.
He's just a boy.
Obi-Wan can no longer help him.
The Force is strong with him.
The son of Skywalker
must not become a Jedi.
If he could be turned...
he would become a powerful ally.
Yes.
He would be a great asset.
Can it be done?
He will join us or die, master.
I'm sure it's delicious. I just don't
understand why we can't see Yoda now.
Patience. For the Jedi,
it is time to eat as well.
Eat. Eat.
Hot.
Good food. Good.
How far away is Yoda?
Will it take us long to get there?
Not far. Yoda not far.
Patience.
Soon you will be with him.
Root leaf. I cook.
Why wish you become Jedi?
Mostly 'cause of my father, I guess.
Father.
Powerful Jedi was he.
- Powerful Jedi.
- Oh, come on.
How could you know my father?
You don't even know who I am.
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
We're wasting our time!
I cannot teach him.
The boy has no patience.
He will learn patience.
Much anger in him...
like his father.
Was I any different
when you taught me?
No.
- He is not ready.
- Yoda.
I am ready.
I can be a Jedi.
Ben, tell him I'm...
Ready, are you?
What know you ready?
For 800 years have I trained Jedi.
My own counsel will I keep
on who is to be trained.
A Jedi must have
the deepest commitment...
the most serious mind.
This one a long time have I watched.
All his life
has he looked away...
to the future,
to the horizon.
Never his mind on where he was...
what he was doing.
Adventure.
Excitement.
A Jedi craves not these things.
You are reckless.
So was I, if you remember.
He is too old.
Yes, too old to begin the training.
But I've learned so much.
- Will he finish what he begins?
- I won't fail you.
I'm not afraid.
You will be.
- Sir, if I may venture an opinion...
- I'm not interested in your opinion.
There's something out there.
- Where?
- Outside in the cave.
There it is. Listen!
- I'm going out there.
- Are you crazy?
I just got this bucket together.
I won't let it get torn apart.
Then I'm going with you.
I think it might be better
if I stay behind and guard the ship.
Oh, no.
This ground sure feels strange.
It doesn't feel like rock.
There's an awful lot
of moisture in here.
I don't know.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Yeah.
Watch out!
It's all right. It's all right.
Yeah, that's what I thought... mynock.
Chewie, check the rest of the ship and
make sure there are no more attached...
chewing on the power cables.
Mynocks?
Go inside. We'll clean them off
if there are any more.
Go away!
Go away, beastly thing! Shoo!
Wait a minute.
- Chewie, let's get out of here!
- The Empire is still out there!
No time to discuss this
in committee!
I am not a committee!
You can't make the jump to light speed
in this asteroid field.
Sit down, sweetheart.
We're taking off.
- Look!
- I see it.
- We're doomed!
- The cave is collapsing.
- This is no cave.
- What?
Yes, run.
Yes.
A Jedi's strength
flows from the Force.
But beware of the dark side.
Anger, fear, aggression...
The dark side
of the Force are they.
Easily they flow,
quick to join you in a fight.
If once you start down
the dark path...
forever will it dominate
your destiny.
Consume you it will,
as it did Obi-Wan's apprentice.
Vader.
- Is the dark side stronger?
- No, no.
Quicker, easier, more seductive.
How am I to know
the good side from the bad?
You will know...
when you are calm,
at peace...
passive.
A Jedi uses the Force
for knowledge and defense...
never for attack.
- But tell me why I can't...
- No. There is no why.
Nothing more
will I teach you today.
Clear your mind of questions.
There's something not right here.
I feel cold.
- Death.
- That place...
is strong with
the dark side of the Force.
A domain of evil it is.
In you must go.
What's in there?
Only what you take with you.
Your weapons...
you will not need them.
Bounty hunters.
We don't need their scum.
- Yes, sir.
- Those rebels won't escape us.
Sir, we have a priority signal
from the Stardestroyer Avenger.
Right.
There will be a substantial reward for
the one who finds the Millennium Falcon.
You are free to use
any methods necessary...
but I want them alive.
No disintegrations.
- As you wish.
- Lord Vader.
My lord, we have them.
Thank goodness
we're coming out of the asteroid field.
Let's get out of here.
Ready for light speed?
One, two...
three!
It's not fair.
Transfer circuits aren't working.
It's not my fault.
- No light speed?
- It's not my fault.
Sir, we just lost
the main rear deflector shield.
One more direct hit
on the back quarter and we're done for.
Turn her around.
Turn her around! I'm gonna
put all power in the front shield.
- You're gonna attack?
- The odds of surviving...
a direct assault
on an imperial Stardestroyer...
Shut up!
They're moving to attack position.
Shields up.
Track them. They may
come around for another pass.
Captain Needa, the ship no longer
appears on our scopes.
They can't have disappeared. No ship
that small has a cloaking device.
- There's no trace of them.
- Captain, Lord Vader demands an update.
Get a shuttle ready.
I shall assume full responsibility for
losing them and apologize to Lord Vader.
- Meanwhile, continue to scan the area.
- Yes, Captain Needa.
Use the Force.
Yes.
Now, the stone.
Feel it.
Concentrate!
Oh, no.
We'll never get it out now.
So certain are you.
Always with you
it cannot be done.
Hear you nothing that I say?
Master, moving stones
around is one thing.
This is totally different.
No. No different.
Only different in your mind.
You must unlearn
what you have learned.
- All right. I'll give it a try.
- Try not.
Do...
or do not.
There is no try.
I can't. It's too big.
Size matters not.
Look at me.
Judge me by my size, do you?
And well you should not...
for my ally is the Force.
And a powerful ally it is.
Life creates it...
makes it grow.
Its energy surrounds us...
and binds us.
Luminous beings are we,
not this crude matter.
You must feel
the Force around you.
Here, between you, me...
the tree, the rock...
everywhere.
Yes...
even between
the land and the ship.
You want the impossible.
I don't believe it.
That is why you fail.
Apology accepted,
Captain Needa.
Lord Vader, our ships have completed
their scan and found nothing.
If the Millennium Falcon
went into light speed...
it'll be on the other side
of the galaxy now.
Alert all commands.
Calculate every possible destination
along their last known trajectory.
- Yes, my lord. We'll find them.
- Don't fail me again...
Admiral.
Alert all commands.
Deploy the fleet.
Captain Solo,
this time you have gone too far.
I will not be quiet, Chewbacca.
Why doesn't anyone listen to me?
The fleet's beginning to break up.
Go stand by the manual release
for the landing claw.
I really don't see
how that's going to help.
Surrender is a perfectly acceptable
alternative in extreme circumstances.
The Empire may be
gracious enough...
- Thank you.
- What did you have in mind next?
If they follow standard
imperial procedure...
they'll dump their garbage
before they go to light speed.
- Then we just float away.
- With the rest of the garbage.
Then what?
Then we gotta find a safe port
somewhere around here.
Any ideas?
- Where are we?
- The Anoat system.
The Anoat system.
There's not much there.
Oh, wait.
This is interesting.
- Lando.
- Lando system?
Lando's not a system.
He's a man. Lando Calrissian.
Card player, gambler.
- A scoundrel. You'd like him.
- Thanks.
Bespin. It's pretty far,
but I think we can make it.
- A mining colony?
- Yeah, a tibanna gas mine.
Lando conned somebody out of it.
We go back a long way,
Lando and me.
- Can you trust him?
- No.
But he's got no love for the Empire.
I can tell you that.
Here we go, Chewie.
Stand by. Detach.
You do have your moments.
Not many of them,
but you do have them.
Concentrate.
Feel the Force flow.
Yes.
Good.
Calm.
Yes.
Through the Force,
things you will see.
Other places.
The future. The past.
Old friends long gone.
Control, control.
You must learn control.
I saw a city in the clouds.
Friends you have there.
- They were in pain.
- It is the future you see.
Future?
Will they die?
Difficult to see.
Always in motion is the future.
I've gotta go to them.
Decide you must
how to serve them best.
If you leave now,
help them you could...
but you would destroy all
for which they have fought and suffered.
No, I don't have a landing permit.
I'm trying to reach Lando Calrissian.
Wait a minute!
Let me explain!
You will not deviate
from your present course.
- Rather touchy, aren't they?
- I thought you knew this person.
That was a long time ago.
I'm sure he's forgotten about that.
Permission granted to land
on Platform 327.
Thank you.
Nothing to worry about.
We go way back, Lando and me.
Who's worried?
No one to meet us.
I don't like this.
- What would you like?
- They did let us land.
Look, don't worry.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Trust me.
See? My friend.
Keep your eyes open.
Hey.
Why, you slimy, double-crossing,
no-good swindler.
You've got a lot of guts coming here,
after what you pulled.
How you doin', you old pirate?
So good to see you!
- I never thought I'd see you again.
- Well, he seems very friendly.
Yes. Very friendly.
What are you doing here?
Repairs. I thought
you could help me out.
- What have you done to my ship?
- Your ship?
Hey, remember,
you lost her to me fair and square.
How you doin', Chewbacca?
Still hanging around with this loser?
Hello.
What have we here?
Welcome. I'm Lando Calrissian.
I'm the administrator of this facility.
- And who might you be?
- Leia.
Welcome, Leia.
All right, all right.
You old smoothie.
Hello, sir. I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
My facilities are at your...
Well, really!
- What's wrong with the Falcon?
- Hyperdrive.
- I'll get my people to work on her.
- Good.
That ship saved my life
quite a few times.
She's the fastest
hunk of junk in the galaxy.
How's the gas mine?
Still paying off for you?
Not as well as I'd like. We're a small
outpost and not very self-sufficient.
I've had supply problems
of every kind.
I've had labor difficulties.
- What's so funny?
- You. Listen to you.
You sound like a businessman,
a responsible leader.
Who'd have thought that, huh?
Seeing you sure brings back
a few things.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm responsible these days.
It's the price you pay
for being successful.
Nice to see a familiar face.
How rude!
That sounds like
an R2 unit in there.
I wonder if...
Hello?
How interesting.
- Who are you?
- Oh, my. I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude.
Please don't get up.
Luke, you must complete the training.
I can't keep the vision out of my head.
They're my friends. I've gotta help them.
You must not go.
- But Han and Leia will die if I don't.
- You don't know that.
Even Yoda cannot see their fate.
But I can help them.
I feel the Force.
But you cannot control it.
This is a dangerous time for you...
when you will be tempted
by the dark side of the Force.
Yes, yes.
To Obi-Wan you listen.
The cave.
Remember your failure at the cave.
But I've learned
so much since then.
Master Yoda, I promise to return
and finish what I've begun.
You have my word.
It is you and your abilities
the emperor wants.
That is why your friends
are made to suffer.
That's why I have to go.
Luke, I don't want to lose you
to the emperor the way I lost Vader.
You won't.
Stopped they must be.
On this all depends.
Only a fully trained Jedi knight,
with the Force as his ally...
will conquer Vader
and his emperor.
If you end your training now...
if you choose the quick and easy path,
as Vader did...
you will become an agent of evil.
Patience.
- And sacrifice Han and Leia?
- If you honor what they fight for...
yes.
If you choose to face Vader,
you will do it alone.
I cannot interfere.
I understand.
R2, fire up the converters.
Luke!
Don't give in to hate.
That leads to the dark side.
Strong is Vader.
Mind what you have learned.
Save you it can.
I will.
And I'll return. I promise.
Told you, I did.
Reckless is he.
Now...
matters are worse.
That boy is our last hope.
No, there is another.
The ship's almost finished. Two or three
more things and we're in great shape.
The sooner the better.
Something's wrong here.
No one has seen or knows
anything about 3PO.
He's been gone too long
to have gotten lost.
Relax.
I'll talk to Lando
and see what I can find out.
I don't trust Lando.
Well, I don't trust him either,
but he is my friend.
Besides, we'll soon be gone.
Then you're as good as gone,
aren't you?
What happened?
Where?
Found him in a junk pile?
What a mess.
Chewie, you think you can repair him?
- Lando's got people that can fix him.
- No, thanks.
I'm sorry.
Am I interrupting anything?
Not really.
You look absolutely beautiful.
You truly belong here
with us among the clouds.
Thank you.
Would you join me
for a little refreshment?
Everyone's invited, of course.
Having trouble with your droid?
No. No problem. Why?
So you see, since we're
a small operation...
we don't fall into
the jurisdiction of the Empire.
- So you're part of the Mining Guild?
- No, not actually.
Our operation is small enough
not to be noticed.
Which is advantageous
for everybody...
since our customers are anxious to avoid
attracting attention to themselves.
Aren't you afraid the Empire's
gonna find out, shut you down?
It's always been a danger that looms like
a shadow over everything we've built here.
But things have developed
that'll ensure security.
I've just made a deal that'll keep
the Empire out of here forever.
We would be honored
if you would join us.
I had no choice.
They arrived right before you did.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
No, 3PO's with them.
Just hang on.
We're almost there.
I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude.
No, please don't get up.
Stormtroopers? Here?
We're in danger.
I must tell the others.
Oh, no! I've been shot!
Lord Vader.
You may take Captain Solo
to Jabba the Hutt...
after I have Skywalker.
He's no good to me dead.
He will not be
permanently damaged.
Lord Vader, what about Leia
and the Wookiee?
They must never again leave this city.
That wasn't part of our agreement, nor
was giving Han to this bounty hunter!
Perhaps you think you're
being treated unfairly?
No.
Good. It would be unfortunate
if I had to leave a garrison here.
This deal is getting worse
all the time.
Oh, yes, that's very good.
I like that.
Something's not right
because now I can't see.
That's much better.
Wait. Wait.
Oh, my!
What have you done?
I'm backwards!
You flea-bitten furball!
Only an overgrown mophead like you
would be stupid enough...
I feel terrible.
Why are they doing this?
They never even asked me
any questions.
- Get out of here, Lando.
- Shut up and listen.
Vader's agreed
to turn Leia and Chewie over to me.
They'll have to stay here,
but they'll be safe.
- And Han?
- Vader's given him to the bounty hunter.
- Vader wants us all dead.
- He doesn't want you at all.
He's after somebody
called Skywalker.
- Lord Vader set a trap for him.
- And we're the bait.
- He's on his way.
- Perfect.
You fixed us all real good,
didn't you?
My friend.
Stop!
I've done all I can.
Sorry I couldn't do better,
but I got my own problems.
Yeah.
You're a real hero.
You certainly
have a way with people.
This facility is crude...
but it should be adequate
to freeze Skywalker...
for his journey to the emperor.
Lord Vader,
ship approaching, X-wing class.
Good. Monitor Skywalker
and allow him to land.
Lord Vader, we only use this facility
for carbon freezing. It might kill him.
I do not want
the emperor's prize damaged.
We will test it on Captain Solo.
If you'd attached my legs I wouldn't
be in this ridiculous position.
Now remember, Chewbacca,
you have a responsibility for me...
so don't do anything foolish.
What's going on, buddy?
You're being put into carbon freeze.
What if he doesn't survive?
He's worth a lot to me.
The Empire will compensate you
if he dies. Put him in.
Chewbacca, stop!
No, Chewie, stop!
You're going to get us all killed!
Yes, stop. I'm not ready to die.
Hey! Hey!
Listen to me.
Chewie, this won't help me.
Hey, save your strength.
There'll be another time.
The princess.
You have to take care of her.
Do you hear me?
- I love you.
- I know.
What's going on?
Turn round. I can't see.
They've encased him in carbonite.
He should be quite
well-protected...
if he survived
the freezing process, that is.
Well, Calrissian, did he survive?
Yes, he's alive.
And in perfect hibernation.
He's all yours, bounty hunter.
Reset the chamber for Skywalker.
Skywalker has just landed, lord.
Good. See to it
that he finds his way in here.
Calrissian...
take the princess
and the Wookiee to my ship.
You said they'd be left in
the city under my supervision.
I am altering the deal.
Pray I don't alter it any further.
Luke, don't! It's a trap!
It's a trap!
The Force is with you,
young Skywalker.
But you are not a Jedi yet.
Well done.
Hold them in the security tower.
And keep it quiet.
Move.
- What do you think you're doing?
- We're getting out of here.
I knew all along.
It had to be a mistake.
Do you think that
after what you did to Han...
- I had no choice.
- What are you doing? Trust him!
We understand, don't we, Chewie?
He had no choice.
I'm just trying to help.
We don't need any of your help.
What?
- It sounds like Han.
- There's still a chance to save Han...
at the east... platform.
I'm terribly sorry about all this.
After all, he's only a Wookiee.
Put Captain Solo
in the cargo hold.
R2, where have you been?
Wait. Turn around, you woolly...
Hurry! We're trying to save
Han from the bounty hunter.
Well, at least
you're still in one piece.
Look what's happened to me.
Oh, no!
Chewie, they're behind you!
You have learned much, young one.
You'll find I'm full of surprises.
Your destiny lies with me, Skywalker.
Obi-Wan knew this to be true.
All too easy.
Perhaps you're not as strong
as the emperor thought.
Impressive.
Most impressive.
Obi-Wan has taught you well.
You have controlled your fear.
Now, release your anger.
Only your hatred can destroy me.
The security code
has been changed.
R2, you can tell the computer
to override the security systems.
R2, hurry.
Attention.
This is Lando Calrissian. Attention.
The Empire has taken control
of the city.
I advise everyone to leave
before more imperial troops arrive.
This way.
Well, don't blame me.
I'm an interpreter.
I'm not supposed to know a power socket
from a computer terminal.
We're not interested in the hyperdrive
on the Falcon. It's fixed!
Just open the door,
you stupid lump!
I never doubted you for a second.
Wonderful!
That hurts! Bend down,
you thoughtless... Ow!
Go!
I thought that hairy beast
would be the end of me.
Of course I've looked better.
You are beaten.
It is useless to resist.
Don't let yourself be destroyed
as Obi-Wan did.
There is no escape.
Don't make me destroy you.
You do not yet realize
your importance.
You have only begun
to discover your power.
Join me...
and I will complete your training.
With our combined strength...
we can end
this destructive conflict...
and bring order to the galaxy.
I'll never join you!
If you only knew the power
of the dark side.
Obi-Wan never told you
what happened to your father.
He told me enough.
He told me you killed him.
I am your father.
That's not true.
That's impossible!
Search your feelings.
You know it to be true.
You can destroy the emperor.
He has foreseen this.
It is your destiny.
Join me...
and together we can rule the galaxy
as father and son.
Come with me.
It is the only way.
Ben.
Ben, please.
Hear me.
- We've got to go back.
- What?
- I know where Luke is.
- What about those fighters?
Chewie, just do it.
All right, all right!
Alert my Stardestroyer
to prepare for my arrival.
Look, someone's up there.
It's Luke.
Chewie, slow down.
We'll get under him.
Lando, open the top hatch.
Okay. Easy, Chewie.
- Lando?
- Okay, let's go.
All right, Chewie. Let's go.
I'll be back.
Stardestroyer.
All right, Chewie.
Ready for light speed.
If your people fixed the hyperdrive.
All the coordinates are set.
It's now or never.
Punch it!
They told me they fixed it.
I trusted them!
It's not my fault!
They'll be in range
of our tractor beam in moments, lord.
Did your men deactivate the hyperdrive
on the Millennium Falcon?
- Yes, my lord.
- Good.
Prepare the boarding party
and set your weapons for stun.
- Yes, my lord. Lieutenant.
- Yes, sir.
Noisy brute. Why don't we
just go into light speed?
We can't?
How would you know
the hyperdrive is deactivated?
The city's central computer told you?
R2-D2, you know better
than to trust a strange computer.
Ouch! Pay attention
to what you're doing.
Father.
Son, come with me.
Ben.
Why didn't you tell me?
It's Vader.
Luke, it is your destiny.
Why didn't you tell me?
Alert all commands.
Ready for the tractor beam.
R2, come back at once!
You haven't finished with me yet.
You don't know how to fix the
hyperdrive. Chewbacca can do it.
I'm standing here in pieces
and you're having delusions of grandeur!
You did it!
- Luke, we're ready for take-off.
- Good luck, Lando.
When we find Jabba the Hutt and
that bounty hunter, we'll contact you.
I'll meet you at
the rendezvous point on Tatooine.
Princess, we'll find Han.
I promise.
Chewie, I'll be waiting
for your signal.
Take care, you two.
May the Force be with you.